ligonier.org 2018-12-31

# Ligonier Ministries

### **Privacy Statement**

Ligonier Ministries is committed to respecting the privacy rights of all parties who interact with the ministry, including donors. The following outlines our privacy policy and details the measures we have taken to safeguard and protect your privacy. Information you provide to us is understood to be in agreement with the policies detailed below.

### What information does Ligonier Ministries collect?

Ligonier Ministries collects and stores your personal contact information only when you supply it to us. This is ordinarily for the purpose of creating an account, processing a transaction, or requesting to receive updates. We do not store your credit card information.

Our system may also gather information about the areas you visit on Ligonier.org and in our various apps as well as the IP address you used to connect. This information is used internally for two reasons: 1) to personalize your experience and 2) to prevent fraudulent activity.

### What does Ligonier Ministries do with your personal information?

Your information is used to process orders, accept gifts, and communicate with you. Also, by storing your personal information on a secure server, Ligonier Ministries is able to shorten your checkout process and allow you to check the status of your orders online.

### Does Ligonier Ministries share any personal information it collects with outside parties?

Ligonier Ministries does not trade or sell any personal information to third parties, nor send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations. However, we may share your personal data in the following circumstances: third parties providing services on our behalf. In order to carry out your requests, to make various features, services, and resources available to you through our websites and apps, and to respond to your inquiries, we may share your personal data or usage data with third parties that perform functions on our behalf, such as companies or individuals that: host or operate our websites; analyze data; provide customer service; mail resource samples or manage payments; advertisers; or other third parties that provide marketing assistance.

### Does Ligonier Ministries safeguard my personal information?

Ligonier Ministries has implemented a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information. Your personal information is stored behind a secure network and is only accessible by designated staff, and is used for the purpose for which you provided the information. When you place orders or access your personal information, we offer the use of a secure server. All sensitive information supplied by you is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and securely stored.

Ligonier Ministries complies with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard that requires us to:

  * Protect data that is stored with you
  * Implement security systems and applications such as firewalls and antivirus software
  * Have a firewall at all times to protect data
  * Use anti-virus software and have it updated regularly
  * Have your own unique system and security passwords
  * Encrypt transmission of cardholder data and other sensitive data across all public networks
  * Restrict employee business access to data based on the needs and job description
  * Track and monitor all access to network resources and cardholder data
  * Maintain an information security policy

### Does Ligonier Ministries provide a way to update or remove my personal information?

Ligonier Ministries provides an account dashboard feature on our website that allows you to modify and/or remove personal information. This page can be accessed by clicking on the "My Account" link at the top right of most pages. All of your information within your profile is secure and accessible only by you or limited staff.

### How does Ligonier Ministries use my email address?

Your email address is used to create and identify your account on Ligonier.org. Your email address is also used by Ligonier Ministries to correspond with you about orders you may have placed or to keep you updated with ministry news and other information. We may also use your email address to notify you about important functionality changes to the web site. If you would rather not receive this information or would like to opt-out of receiving email of this kind, simply click on the "Unsubscribe" link that appears on the bottom of any email and follow the simple instructions.

### What is Ligonier Ministries' return policy?

Ligonier Ministries has a 30-day return policy for most items in new condition. You may return the product with a description of the problem and why you are returning it. The return should come from the original purchaser of the product. For refunds or any other questions, please contact service@ligonier.org or call 800.435.4343.

### Does Ligonier Ministries use cookies?cookie

Ligonier Ministries uses technologies such as "cookies" (small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters that we put on your computer) and other similar tracking technologies (like web beacons, tags, and scripts) to help us better understand user behavior, measure the effectiveness of web searches and advertisements, and customize content and advertisements. We treat information collected by cookies as anonymous information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Likewise, when anonymous information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

To browse without cookies, you can either configure your browser to reject all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is set, or manually turn off select cookies in our [Cookie Policy](https://www.ligonier.org/cookies). Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. Even if you choose to browse without cookies, you can still access most of the features on Ligonier.org.

### How can I remove my name from Ligonier Ministries' direct mail or email list?

To have your email address removed from our list of addresses that receive information about new resources, services, sales, and promotions, simply click on the "Unsubscribe" link that appears at the bottom of any email you've received from us and follow the simple instructions.

You may remove your personal information from our direct mail list by contacting us in writing at, Ligonier Ministries 421 Ligonier Court Sanford, FL 32771, by emailing us at service@ligonier.org, or by calling 800.435.4343.

### What is the privacy policy for offline donors?

The same privacy terms outlined above applies to offline donors. Ligonier Ministries collects and stores your personal contact information only when you supply it to us. This is ordinarily for the purpose of creating an account, processing a transaction, or requesting to receive updates.

We do not store your credit card information. Your information is used to process orders, accept gifts, and communicate with you. Your personal information is stored behind a secure network and is only accessible by designated staff, and is used for the purpose for which you provided the information.

Ligonier Ministries does not trade, sell or share any personal information to third parties, nor send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations.

### Your Consent

You acknowledge that this Privacy Policy and [Cookie Policy](https://www.ligonier.org/cookies) is part of the Terms of Service and you agree that using this site signifies your assent to Ligonier Ministries' Privacy Policy and Cookie Policy. Ligonier Ministries reserves the right to change the Terms of Service, including this Privacy Policy or Cookie Policy at any time, without advanced notice. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post the changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

### Tell us what you think

If you have any comments or questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us in writing at, Ligonier Ministries 421 Ligonier Court Sanford, FL 32771, by emailing us at webmaster@ligonier.org, or by calling 800.435.4343.
